[Episode 12]
[Small, Big]
Miss, wait a moment. I'll find you a game.
I'll gamble with you.
Please sit, Sir.
In that case,
let's begin.
The game begins.
Enjoy yourselves, guests.
The points are the same.
According to the rules
of Xingrong Gambling House,
the banker has the advantage.
Therefore, this lady wins.
In a gambling house,
one's birth is not asked,
the status is ignored,
and only skill matters.
You won this round
because of the house rules.
If you ignore the rules,
one day, you will also
be cast out of the game.
If you set the rules,
I'll have no choice but to accept.
But at this moment, you must accept defeat.
Since you're so eager to win,
I'll play along to the end.
Again.
This lady wins.
This lady wins again.
Mr. He, since you have no more silver,
you have no right to gamble with me.
Let's call it a day.
Thank you, honored guest.
Our gambling house has many other games.
Why not step into a private room and rest?
Better luck is yet to come.
Guests, please rest for a moment.
Situ Xue was not sent by me.
Why is Your Majesty following me?
Next time you investigate a place like this,
take someone with you.
But the Censorate has no one else
apart from the "handsome young man" you said.
Do you want the entire gambling house to know
that the ruler of the country came here
to gamble and vent with you?
Outside the palace gates, just call me He Du.
After Shazhou,
there is no more He Du.
What Your Majesty says and does
teaches me the ruler-subject divide.
Let us each stay in our proper place.
What are you doing?
Yue.
Gui.
This is the silver I've saved up this month.
Give it to Ms. Meng and beg her to show mercy
to see if she can hold off
sending you up to the second floor.
Here.
Gui,
thank you for always pulling strings for me.
But now, Mr. Hao has personally named me.
I can't escape tomorrow's game
on the second floor.
I embroidered this handkerchief myself.
Just keep it as a keepsake.
I won't let you go upstairs.
There are still several hours left.
I'll go gather the money.
Yue, wait for me.
Honored guests,
this gambling house has many new games.
Let me take you for a few more hands.
Gui, I hear your gambling house
is full of hidden talent.
I came to gather some news at first,
but I never thought
that I would win so much silver.
What news are you trying to gather?
Perhaps I can help.
Do you know about the Huxiao Gang?
If you want news on the Huxiao Gang,
wait for me at the house's back door
with 600 tales of silver.
[Wanchun Pavilion]
After all these years,
you have finally achieved your wish
and become a gang leader
who commands respect far and wide.
When my mother and I
were abandoned by that brat,
I swore to myself in secret
that I must become strong.
Only by seizing the initiative
can I avoid being discarded like a dog.
Alright, it's all in the past now.
Pavilion Master Liu.
I'll go take a look.
Where is the silver?
What exactly do you know?
You must first let us know its value.
What if you go back on your word
after I speak?
Give me the silver first.
What if you are deceiving us?
This gambling house's second floor
holds an unspeakable secret.
The one protecting it is the Huxiao Gang.
What secret?
I've been here for a year now.
I know Huxiao Gang's dealings
with the gambling house.
If you want to know more,
give me the silver first.
I need to hurry and save Yue.
- Who is Yue?
- Yue is from my hometown.
She is about to be sent to the second floor.
We'll go with you.
No.
If the gambling house
finds out about our deal,
both Yue and I will die.
I beg of you.
I am truly desperate for this money.
Wait for me for an hour.
Just an hour.
I swear that I will definitely come back.
Thank you.
He said Yue is about to be sent
to the second floor.
What secret exactly is hidden
on the second floor?
Since it is related to the Huxiao Gang,
we need to get up to the second floor
and see what's there.
It seems to be someone from the Censorate.
They came to the Wanxiang Pavilion
to track your whereabouts.
They show up at our door?
Meng Ting Hui didn't die.
And you killed Wan Kai.
Now
the court is targeting the Huxiao Gang.
What do we do next?
What is there to fear?
She escaped last time,
but I'd like to see
how capable she is to slip away
from my grasp again.
No need to worry.
Don't we have someone in the court?
But I am worried about you.
Even he might not truly protect you.
Have you forgotten how he used you before?
The higher the position,
the crueler he becomes.
The higher the position, the better he's
at weighing the gains and losses,
and the more he fears being exposed.
You carry on with the plan
to keep the money coming.
Don't panic.
As for Meng Ting Hui,
sooner or later,
I will make her fall into my hands.
Look at you.
Inside the Wanxiang Pavilion,
if anyone dares to leak my news,
just kill them.
I know.
Remember,
anyone in this world can betray me
except you.
Because I can't bear to harm you.
In this world, you can distrust anyone,
but you must trust me.
[Xingrong Gambling House]
It's already been an hour.
Let's go in and take a look.
What happened?
Gui?
S-Save
Yue.
What are you looking at? Move aside!
Never seen a gambler took his own life?
Come on.
What bad luck.
[Censorate]
The food is ready. Let's eat first.
Wan Kai left this behind before he died.
What exactly was his intention?
With my years of experience
traveling the world,
roaming all the great mountains,
and having read extensively...
I also don't know.
I suggest we eat first instead.
Could this be a map?
The Huxiao Gang tried to kill him.
He harbored a deep grudge.
So he wanted to use this map
to guide us to find the Huxiao Gang's base.
You make a fair point, Miss Shen.
But he was barely clinging to life back then.
Drawing a map would have taken a long time.
A message that was conveyed
at the brink of death
might be related to identity.
You make an even fairer point, Miss Meng.
Identity?
Who could it be?
The lead on Wan Kai is cut off.
What about you two?
Have you found anything on Changle Street?
Everything else is normal.
But I went to the Wanxiang Pavilion
for a few days
and never saw the Pavilion Master.
Normally, the Pavilion Master
should greet guests personally.
Other than that, there is nothing suspicious.
I checked the tea house, medical clinic,
and other places
and haven't found anything suspicious so far.
Since something feels off,
we must stay alert.
For now, the clearest lead
related to the Huxiao Gang
is that gambling house.
Then seal it off.
According to the Laws of Ning Empire,
sealing it off requires solid evidence.
The gambling house
looks normal on the outside.
And gambling isn't banned in Ning Empire,
so it's still a legal business.
Let's not alert the target for now.
There is just one thing
I need to entrust to you.
[Xingrong Gambling House]
No changing bets!
- No changing bets!
- Please.
Come on, hurry up and bet!
- No changing bets!
- Big!
- Reveal it!
No changing bets!
Please come inside.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
Zhi Li, Yin Qing, and Fu Zhi
emptied their pockets
to barely scrape together 1,000 taels.
We need to win ten rounds in a row
to make it 10,000 taels.
Luckily, we have you, Mr. He.
Since we're going to the second floor,
you must have had the silver ready.
I knew it.
When it comes to generosity,
Who in Ning Empire would have the nerve
to steal your thunder, Mr. He?
This is my personal savings
scraped together over half a year.
But seriously,
you're not as stingy
as Mr. Shen complained you were.
- What did you say?
- Mr. He, let's focus on the business.
Another round.
What a big spender!
I go with big.
Stingy.
Ten thousand taels on big.
One round decides the winner.
Ten thousand taels? I bet on small.
Small. I bet on small too.
Alright. No changing bets.
Small!
Big.
With your earlier gesture
of throwing away a fortune,
I thought you were a master.
As expected, you're really a "master".
Indeed.
Ten thousand taels
couldn't even buy a bit of fun.
Since the gambling here is boring,
let's find another place.
Alright.
Gentlemen, please wait.
If a high roller like you leaves,
my boss will say
I don't know how to treat guests.
What? Are we not free to leave?
You misunderstand.
We are the only gambling house
guaranteed by capital officials.
We'd never wrong our guests.
Guaranteed by capital officials?
That is interesting.
The way you splashed a fortune here today
was truly impressive.
My boss specifically had me
invite you to the second floor
to experience more interesting games.
Please do us the honor.
[From the Gambling House]
So you already knew those ten thousand taels
weren't coming back.
It's a pity I bet on big.
It will be deducted from your salary.
Once on the second floor,
you must not speak much.
May I ask what the game is tonight?
It wouldn't be right to bet without knowing.
All games are carefully arranged by us.
If you two find it interesting, just join in.
Considering it's your first time here,
I'll give you a hint as an exception.
Tonight is a blind bet.
The stakes are antique porcelain vases.
What's so special about mere antiques?
Please be patient, Sir.
After you two have won the bid,
you will understand
the intrigue and pleasure within.
Remember, you must be silent during the game.
A silent gamble
holds the true pleasure.
[From the Gambling House]
Gentlemen, please.
The real game has begun.
The rules for today's game are as follows.
You need only note the number
of your chosen porcelain vase in your letter,
and after three gong strikes,
the highest bidder wins the treasure.
These antique porcelain vases
are nothing special.
But these women
are each gentle and virtuous,
and their every move
is graceful as a noble lady's.
It's a gamble on vases.
But why are they dressed as scholars?
They have fair skin,
without the calluses of poor girls
or the coquettishness of courtesans.
Could they also be forced women like Yue?
Everything here is eerie.
We must find Yue first
[Yue]
to know the truth.
[Vase No. 18, Vase No. 12]
[Yue]
Tonight's top piece is this willow-leaf vase
from the previous dynasty.
Congratulations to this honored guest,
who won the top prize
with a bid of twenty thousand taels.
[Yue]
Gui! Gui!
She is Yue.
Gui!
What they are betting on
is not any vase at all.
Follow them.
Harder.
A little harder.
Good.
Good, that's the force.
Sir, it's you.
What brings you here?
Come, sit down.
Mr. Hao,
you're living quite comfortably.
It seems you've forgotten
whose gamble house this is.
Sir, w-what are you saying?
I would never dare to forget
that our master is the ultimate owner
of this gambling house.
Well,
business has been booming these days,
so I thought I'd relax a bit.
By the way, Sir,
here is the recent income
of our gambling house.
Please take a look.
Not bad.
I am quite reassured
with the gambling house in your hands.
But Mr. Hao,
now that your purse is full,
don't forget the rules.
How could I dare forget?
I was just thinking
about offering more tribute to Master.
By the way, Sir,
if the east-end gambling house
belongs to me as well,
you will also have a share in it.
Wait a moment, Sir.
Sir.
There is one more thing.
Recently, the Censorate--
Mr. Hao!
Mr. Hao.
You want to die?
How many times have I said it?
Knock before entering.
Yes, I'll go back and knock now.
Come back.
Speak. What is it?
If you don't have something serious to say,
I'll skin you alive.
Mr. Hao, this is Zhai,
the gatekeeper of our gambling house.
He says he has something confidential
to tell you.
Confidential?
Mr. Hao.
You, a gatekeeper!
- What confidential business could you have?
- Mr. Hao!
Every unworthy wretch comes to my door!
Do you think my place is a teahouse?
Mr. Hao, Mr. Hao.
Meng Ting Hui from the Censorate
brought a man to the second floor.
- They are up to no good.
- You're a gatekeeper!
Can you be sure it's her?
Wait.
The Censorate
has been on Changle Street lately,
secretly tracking whereabouts
of Master and me.
Tell your men to be smart.
Don't let her get any dirt on us.
They must not find the secret
on the second floor.
I'll take care of it right away.
Move!
Honored guests,
if you go any further,
you are breaking the rules.
It's Yue.
Yue?
She's still breathing.
They were just here. Where are they now?
- Find them!
- Let's go.
Let's go.
[Censorate]
You...
You are
the female Zhuangyuan
who achieved the Triple First,
Miss Meng.
Did you save me?
It was Gui who asked us to save you.
Gui?
Where is he?
Gui risked his life to save you.
He wanted you to live well.
Gui,
I brought this upon you.
I caused your death.
You are weak. Please don't grieve too much.
If you have any grievances,
feel free to tell Miss Meng.
Yes, Miss Meng will seek justice for you.
We were female students
who would take the next Imperial Exam.
We came from humble and remote origins.
Thankfully, His Majesty restarted
the Imperial Exam for women.
Miss Meng, you strongly backed that,
allowing ordinary women
like us to see a way out.
Later, someone came claiming
to be from the capital's Women's Academy,
picking gifted girls across the prefectures
for advanced studies in the capital.
We believed it to be true.
After entering the capital,
we were imprisoned in a residence.
At first, they taught us
music, chess, calligraphy, and painting.
Later, the top students were taken away
and never seen again.
At the same time, new female students
kept arriving at the residence.
Yue,
where is that residence in the capital?
From home to the capital,
we were always kept
in tightly sealed carriages.
Upon arrival at the residence,
we were forbidden from stepping outside.
How long have you been here?
And how did you meet Gui?
I have been in the capital
for over three months.
By chance, I recognized Gui
who delivered vegetables to the residence.
From him, I learned
that those female students
who were taken away
were all sent to the second floor
of the gambling house,
becoming the playthings of those gamblers
in the form of bets.
Those gamblers are all depraved brutes.
They take pleasure in torturing women,
and their methods are cruel.
Thanks to Gui before,
I was delayed
from being sent to the second floor.
Didn't you think about escaping?
We tried.
We even reported it.
But the officials were in cahoots with them.
After escaping,
we were caught and brought back.
Some of us had our limbs cut off
and were tortured to death.
Unable to bear the humiliation,
many female students
chose suicide.
Do you know
which court officials
are colluding with them?
And who captured you?
I only heard among them
someone called Master Lv Da.
He is Lv Er's older brother.
I saw him before.
Do you know anything
about the guests upstairs?
Especially those who took you away.
They all wore masks.
I only remember
that the man wore a red jade thumb ring
etched with a caged bird on it.
Last night was my first time going up...
up...
Yue.
Miss Meng,
thank you.
I know my health condition.
It's too late.
Listen.
It's the sound of reading.
The realm
may be divided.
The emolument
may be refused.
The blade
can be trampled upon.
But the Mean
cannot be reached.
Yue, I'm here.
I'll take you away.
Gui.
Yue.
- Yue.
- Miss Meng.
Miss Meng, how I wish I could be like you,
to study
and earn a scholarly rank.
Yue?
Yue,
I will definitely make those villains
pay blood for blood.
[Why was Wan Kai killed]
Those gamblers spend lavishly.
They must be men of stature.
And those women
got no help from the authorities,
surely because there are many court officials
among the gamblers.
The Huxiao Gang entertains the officials
with those women
and uses it as leverage
to make them their protective umbrella.
Those women harbored great ambitions,
wanting to contribute to the court,
but fell into the quagmire of officialdom
and had their lives ruined.
What is laughable is that
[Huxiao Gang]
those murderers
sit high in the halls of power
and act with utter impunity.
[Masked Man]
Be it the Huxiao Gang
or corrupt officials,
I will drag you down
from your high places one by one
and grind your bones to ashes.
I'll take men to the gambling house now.
I get how angry you feel.
But only by planning carefully
can we catch them all in one sweep.
I watched Yue die in front of me
with my own eyes.
How can I be calm?
Your Majesty, I'm here to escort you back...